Virkka Hanttu from T4F Finland.
This is Pro's Guide:
Dynamic CQP Fundamentals.
In this episode,
we are going through team
movement, concentrating on
corridors, and movement from room
to room.
The team rules are like traffic
rules: they tell you where you
drive, where you go,
how you group when you turn.
The team members have to be able
to read each other so they can
predict what's going to happen
next, even though they don't see
in the rooms.
As a principle told earlier,
the point man always takes the
biggest threat.
Would it be the open door in the
end of the corridor,
or would it be the tangle?
Second man supports has overall
security.
We have a saying:
number one takes the door,
number two takes the long.
This means, on the corridor,
number one concentrates on the
open door and what's behind it,
and number two provides security
on the corridor.
Everybody else in the stack
supports the actions of number
one and number two.
Then we have a few basic
fundamental rules on team
movement.
First one of them is:
don't fight from the tunnels.
Would it be a doorframe or a
corridor?
Always, when you go into one,
have a plan where you go next.
So when you enter a corridor,
have a plan:
which door are you taking,
what are your next actions,
so you don't have to stop at the
corridor.
Always have a gun pointing on an
opening angle.
This means, if the point man is
going and there are angles
opening, have a gun pointing at
the opening angles.
Would it be opposing door or
T-junction?
Always have a gun pointing to the
opening angle.
Number one man is always right.
This meaning, even though he
doesn't make good tactical
decisions, we don't make a
mistake over a mistake,
so then you correct it.
In this line of work,
your life depends on it,
so you want everything to be as
good as it can get.
So we support each other.
So everybody concentrates on
their own tasks.
This also means that the number
one man has priority.
If he wants to go left,
everybody else follows him
because he doesn't look back.
The guys are supporting.
He has to be able to concentrate
on his own work.
He has the best relative
situational awareness,
so he decides where the stack is
going.
He doesn't look back because the
guys are on his heels,
and when their train starts,
they will follow.
So now we will start by doing
four-man stack corridor movement.
So guys, load and make ready.
First room on the right,
last room on the left.
Good procedure on the corridor.
We go live.
Questions?
All right.
Let's go again.
That was just a little bit
froggy.
Good movement on the corridor.
Number one has the open door,
number two has the long,
and that's how you build it up.
Good movement on the corridor.
Priorities.
Number one has the target,
number two has long.
Good shots before the threshold.
Corners for corners.
Well done.
Next exercise will be covering
while moving.
So if there are openings,
opening up when the number one is
going.
Number two man, three man,
they take the responsibility to
put themselves and their gun
between the number one's back and
the opening threat.
We call this bunkering.
This is how it goes.
Gentlemen, start.
So here, the first man is going
in.
The second man is bunkering him,
so providing cover with his gun
and blades to his back.
The rest of the stack will go in,
and the bunkering man is the last
one to go in.
All right, continue.
Now we are applying the
principles of footwork,
decision making, and shooting for
the rooms in the darkness using
NVGs.
Again, nothing changes.
First exercise will be one-man
entry.
Just footwork, decision making,
good shots.
Load and make ready.
Move.
Next exercise will be NVG
corridor movement.
Nothing changes.
Go.